OLIVIER CASALTA

Commissioning Engineer



3/40 Macaulay Street 8024 Christchurch **NEW ZEALAND**

36-year-old +64 21 026 566 96 olivier.casalta@gmail.com

Capacity to

Strong electrical & mechanical background

10+ years in construction & commissioning



PROFIL F

Personal Statement I am looking for a new challenge that will require technical and managerial skills for challenging projects in Christchurch. My international experience on site allows me to respond to any kind of emergency situations and solve problems that commit responsibility, authority and skills. My last work position in an automation company, leader in the BMS for commercial projects, gave me a very good understanding of New Zealand standards.

I am a NZ resident.



-+ SKILLS

People and Communication After years of employment in small and large companies I have developed an ability to professionally communicate with a wide range of people. This has been constantly redefined through my different assignments in Europe, Africa and New Zealand. I am clear and concise when communicating with fellow staff and clients.

Initiative & Problem solving When I was working in a construction site. I had to face every-day unforeseen events due to supply chain, team organization, site progress and quality. To acknowledge time, efficiency and security, I developed problem solving skills and good task prioritization. Troubleshooting and initiative at solving problems are the core principles that I use every-day at work.

Hard worker

My solid background in France has cemented my values, ethics and integrity. I endeavor to ensure that whatever I do is completed to the best of my ability. I achieve success through working hard and being a self-starter. I am able to acquire skills quickly and can be trusted to be focused on tasks.



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2018 - 2020 1 year + 10 months

SETPOINT SOLUTION LTD, Commissioning Engineer

Christchurch, New Zealand (click here)

- → Commissioning and testing for building and lighting automation industry (SIEMENS)
- → Configuration and programming software
- → Production of CAD drawings
- → Carry out fine tuning and maintenance of mechanical services
- → Commissioning BMS in HVAC for the new major constructions in Christchurch : Shirley Boys Avonside Girls school, QEII pool, CDHB Outpatient Building, New Central Library

2017 - 2018 1 year

SMOOTH AIR PRODUCT LTD, Sales & Estimator Engineer Christchurch, New Zealand

- → Proficiency of G4 building code, HVAC system as per AS1668
- → Pricing of ventilation material for small/large scale construction project
- → Design of ducted system for domestic and commercial projects: Ducting, Grilles, Fan, Heat Recovery Unit, Ducted Heat Pump, Commercial Kitchen Extract
- → Technical advisor and support for Customer Service
- → Control of manufactured products at final stage before delivery

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2009 - 2016 7 years + 1 months

GE POWER SERVICES (ex ALSTOM), Tender & Methods Manager

La Courneuve, France

- → Responsible of field service tender for electrical and boiler scope on all power plants
- → Managing engineers' team for tender and method projects (5+ engineers)
- → Development of methods for field service operations (creation of 3D models with CAD software CATIA to plan service on nuclear equipment)
- → Creating, developing and performing training sessions for technicians and engineers around site's organization

ALSTOM POWER SYSTEMS, Electrical and IC Construction Manager

Narva, Estonia (click here)

- → Responsible of the electrical works for the new thermal power plant (1x300MW)
- → Managing electrical site supervisors and site technical office (15+ engineers and technicians)
- → Design of new arrangements and cabling drawings for site changes
- → Managing electrical subcontractors and assets
- → Responsible for the interfaces with the client and contractual claims

ALSTOM POWER SYSTEMS, Electrical Construction Manager

Flamanville, France

- → Responsible of the electrical works for the new nuclear power plant (1x1650MW)
- → Managing electrical site supervisors (5+ engineers and technicians)
- → Managing subcontractors and assets
- → Managing the interface with the client and contractual claims

ALSTOM POWER SYSTEMS, Electrical Construction Manager Deputy

Terga, Algeria (click here)

- → Supervision of the electrical works for the new gas combined-cycle power plant (3x400MW)
- → Managing electrical site supervisors (7+ technicians)
- → Managing the interface with the partner of consortium

2009 6 months

SPHER X MAROC, Technical Manager

Casablanca, Morocco

- → Management of commissioning teams for the installation and maintenance of medical products
- → Managing electrical site supervisors (5+ technicians)
- → Technical support 24/7 over the country

2005 - 2008 3 years

TDM, Mechatronics Engineer in a work-linked training program

Mérignac, France

- → Design of test bench and on-board systems for aeronautic industry (Thalès, Airbus, Dassault)
- → Responsible of the manufacturing prototypes in production process

2005 5 months

INSERM National Institute of Health and Medical Research, Technician Applied Physics Montpellier, France

- → Responsible of the software application for medical research lead by national PhD medical team
- → Creation of the software application for modelling spontaneous activity of auditive nerve fibres



EDUCATION

2005 - 2008 3 years

Master's engineering specializing in Mechatronics

lle-de France, France

- → Sciences and Technics Institute of Yvelines (ISTY)
- → Recognized NZ qualification (click here)

2003 - 2005 2 years

Two-year university degree in technology (DUT) in Applied Physics

Montpellier, France

→ University institute of technology (IUT)



Languages

French: Mother tongue

English: Fluent: 7+ years of work in an English-speaking environment

: IELTS Academic score 6,5 in May 2017

Computer

Office : Word, Excel, Power Point, Outlook

Project Management : MS Project

CAD & Mechanical : Catia V5, Autocad, Projecad

Computer Systems : C/C++, Python, SQL, Matlab, LabView

Electrical : Athena, DXP, Protel

BMS : Siemens XWorks, Desigo CC, Apogee

Certifications

Electrical NF C 18-510 H2/B2/BR : Ability to conduct electrical works (LV & HV) as site manager

Mechanical M2 MR : Ability to conduct mechanical works as site manager

Driving

Full clean French & NZ & international driving license

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Sport

Freediving (Certified advanced PADI freediver)
Spearfishing (Member of South Island Spearfishing Club)

Climbing (Member of University Canterbury Climbing Club)

Cycling, Chess, Hiking

Music

Guitar player & teacher:

- → Teacher 2003-2005 in "Association de Danse et Musique de Vendargues" for beginner and intermediate level students
- → Player of jazz/rock guitar in many bands in France up to 2009. My bands and I released several CDs of covers and original songs. Live performances.

Hobby

DIY projects, currently designing web applications and building new furnitures from pallets

Travel

First-hand knowledge of cultural differences
Travelled in Samoa, Fiji, Vietnam, Canada, Morocco, Turkey, Algeria, Wales



New Zealand France Referees (Contact details of referees available on request):

- → Setpoint Solution Ltd, Smooth Air Product Ltd
- → GE Power. Colas Rail

Links:

LinkedIn Website

- → Recommendations are also available here
- → For more information about my profile, please see my website:



https://oliviercasalta.github.io/